A Guide to the Papers of Base Hospital 41 1905-2009
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
- Correspondence to and from former Base Hospital 41 members, re: reunion 1966 April, 4 ALS, 1 TLS, Carbon copy 5 TL and 2 TLS, 17 pp. (Box-folder 001-027)
  Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Sidney E. Powers, Letter from the Reunion Committee to Surviving Veterans of the Battle of Paris, Letter from Bess Purvis to conrades, Letter from Glenn B. Updike to Randolph H. Perry, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Bessie B. Purvis, Letter from D. D. Vance to the Reunion Committee, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Glenn B. Updike, Letter from Sidney [E. Powers] to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Douglas D. Vance, Letter from Fred W. St. Clair to Randolph H. Perry, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Sidney E. Powers, Letter from Bernard P. Chamberlain to J. L. Meem, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Fred W. St. Clair, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Sidney E. Powers
- Correspondence to and from former Base Hospital 41 members, re: reunion 1966 May-June, 3 ALS, 1 Photocopy ALS, 4 TLS, Mimeograph and Carbon copy 8 TL and 1 TLS, 1 Nametag, 19 pp. (Box-folder 001-028)
  Letter from Sam L. Brown to Randolph H. Perry, Letter from Sam L. Brown to Thomas Jefferson Inn, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to B. W. Rannells, Letter from Ben B. Leigh to Randolph H. Perry, Letter from Grover C. Ross to Vance, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to B. W. Rannells, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to B. B. Leigh, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to S. L. Brown, Letter from Carroll E. Beach to Randolph H. Perry, Letter from Doug [D. Vance] to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Randolph H. Perry to to Douglas D. Vance, Letter from Bus Eye [John F. Nelson] to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Sidney E. Powers to Comrades and Friends of Base Hospital 41, Letter from George S. Coyle to Pete [Randolph H. Perry], Letter from Randolph H. Perry to to John F. Nelson, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to George S. Coyle, Letter from Randolph H. Perry to Sidney E. Powers
- Correspondence to and from former Base Hospital 41 members, re: reunion 1967-1969, 2 ALS, Mimeograph 1 TLS, 4 TL and 1 TM, 14 pp. (Box-folder 001-029)
  Letter from Sidney E. Powers and John A. Martin to Members of Base Hospital #41, Mailing List, Letter from B.H. #41 Reunion committee to Doctors, Nurses and Enlisted Men of B.H. #41, Letter from George S. Coyle to Bernard Chamberlain, Letter from Van and Emily to Mr. and Mrs. [Bernard] Chamberlain, Letter from B.H. #41 Reunion committee to Doctors, Nurses and Enlisted Men of B.H. #41, Letter from B.H. #41 Reunion committee to Doctors, Nurses and Enlisted Men of B.H. #41
- Correspondence to and from former Base Hospital 41 members, re: reunion 1970-1975, 2 ALS, 1 TL, 3 TLS, Mimeograph and Photocopy 1 ALS, 10 TL, and 2 TLS, 20 pp. (Box-folder 001-030)
  Letter from W. L. Younger to Glenn B. Updike, Letter from Nate to Glenn B. Updike, Letter from Sarah K. Brent to Bernard P. Chamberlain, Letter from Bernard [P. Chamberlain] to Deming [J. Shear], Letter from Sam and Alice [Brown] to Bruce [C. Lightner], Letter from Bruce C. Lightner to Bernard P. Chamberlain, Letter from Richard M. Graham to Bernard P. Chamberlain, Letter from John A. Martin to Loyal Comrades of B.H. 41
- Correspondence to and from former Base Hospital 41 members, re: reunion 1976-193, [n.d.], 7 ALS, 1 TL, 3TLS, Mimeograph and Photocopy 8 TL, and 3 TLS, 26 pp. (Box-folder 001-031)
  Letter from Betty Pettit to Bernard [Chamberlain], Letter from George S. Coyle to Bernard [Chamberlain], Letter from Esther Haswell, Letter from Caroll Beach, Letter from Margaret Martin, Letter from Betty Hackley, Letter from Beverly Brown Dropp to Mr. Wilson, Letter from Bruce C. Lightner to Harry [Wilson], Letter from Annd Freudenberg to mr. Wilson, Letter from Bernard P. Chamberlain to W. Wilhelm Moll, Letter from Charles M. Taylor to Glenn B. Updike, Letter from Glenn B. Updike to Charles M. Taylor, Letter from Glenn B. Updike to the University of Virginia, Letter from the Reunion Committee Base Hospital 41 to the Young Men and Women of Base Hospital #41, Letter from the Reunion Committee to the Hardy Relicts of Base Hospital #41, Letter from the B. H. 41 Reunion Committee to the Very Brave Members of Base Hospital #41, Letter from the Reunion Committee Base Hospital #41 to the Embattled Members of Base Hospital #41
- Minutes: Organization Meeting, Base Hospital 41 1940 May 18, 1 TMs, 3 pp. (Box-folder 001-032)
  The minutes nclude a list of those attending.
- Minutes: Organization Meeting, Base Hospital 41 1940 May, Leaflet w AN, 2 copies, 4 pp. (Box-folder 001-033)
- Roster, Base Hospital 41 1941, Mimeograph 1 TMs, 4 pp. (Box-folder 001-034)
- Roster, Base Hospital 41 1941, Carbon copy 2 TMs, 8 pp. (Box-folder 001-035)
- Roster, Base Hospital 41, A. E. F., Compiled at St. Denis, France, January 1919 1941, Carbon copy, 1 TMs w AN, 4 pp. (Box-folder 001-036)
- Roster, Base Hospital Unit 41, printed for 1941 reunion 1941, Leaflets 5 copies, 20 pp. (Box-folder 001-037)
- Rosters and reunion address lists, Base Hospital 41, 1963, Mimeograph and Carbon copy 6 TMS, 1 photocopy pamphlet w AN, 24 pp. (Box-folder 001-038)
- Rosters, Base Hospital 41, includes brief estimate of reunion costs 1965, 2 TMs, 2 AMs w AN, 15 pp. (Box-folder 001-039)
- Reunion lists of Base Hospital 41 members interested in attending reunion 1965, 6 TMs, 2 Carbon copy TMs, 13 pp. (Box-folder 001-040)
- "Between Convoys" 1918 December, Photocopy newsletter and 4 original newsletters, 20 pp. (Box-folder 002-001)
  Newsletter of Base Hospital 41
- "Between Convoys" 1919 February, Photocopy newsletter, 3 copies 12 pp. (Box-folder 002-002)
- Letter from James J. Kopp to Carol Jenkins re: included photocopied photographs of Base Hospital 41 1981 October 19, 1 TLS, 40 photocopy photographs, 41 pp. (Box-folder 002-003)
  The photocopies are from photographs at the National Library of Medicine. Copies of the images can be ordered from the NLM, History of Medicine website. An actual photograph of one of the photocopied photographs is in Box 002, Folder 64.
- 1966 Roster Base Hospital 41 1966, Mimeograph 1 TMs, 3 copies, 15 pp. (Box-folder 002-004)
- Articles about Douglas D. Vance and Vance's book "Doctor Is My End in Sight?" 1977-78, 8 photocopy newspaper clippings, 9 pp. (Box-folder 002-005)
- Letter from James J. Kopp to Terry Thorkildson re: Base Hospital 41 newsletter 1981 November 18, 1 TLS, 2 pp. (Box-folder 002-006)
- Photocopied photographs of Base Hospital 41 1981, 45 Photocopy photographs, 45 pp. (Box-folder 002-007)
  Photocopies are from photographs at the National Library of Medicine. Copies of the images can be ordered from the NLM, History of Medicine website.
- Reunion lists and 1966 roster, Base Hospital 41 D1966, 4 AMs, 6 Mimeograph TMs, some w AN, 2 Carbon copy TMs, 34 pp. (Box-folder 002-008)
- Reunion notes and minutes, Base Hospital 41 1941 June 7, 1 Leaflet, 3 copies, 6 pp. (Box-folder 002-009)
- "Bicentennial Greetings" Supplement to material taken from a diary of Glenn B. Updike, Sr. 1976 July 4, 1 photocopy TMs, 6 pp. (Box-folder 002-010)
  The excerpts describe Updike's service in World War I.
- Note from Bernard Chamberlain to Mason [S. Byrd] and photocopies of photographs of Base Hospital 41 members D, 1 ALS, 4 Photocopy photographs, 5 pp. (Box-folder 002-011)
  The photocopies are of photographs taken in 1919 and 1921.
- Photograph of Base Hospital 41 reunion group 1968, 1 Photograph, B and W 8x10 (Box-folder 002-012)
  Bottom Row L to R: 1 ?, Jack Curtis, Stuart Rothwell, Scott Atkinson, John S. Martin, James L. Watts, Randolph Perry, "Monk" Younger, Henry Bomberger, "Bus Eye" Nelson, Wm. Vansant; Second Row L to R: 1 ?, Mrs. Alfred Martin, Mrs. S. L. Brown, Mrs. Jack Curtis, Mrs. Stuart Rothwell, Mrs. John S. Martin, Mrs Bruce Lightner (?), 8 ?, Mrs. Scott Atkinson, 10 ?, Mrs. James L. Watts, Mrs. Maynard Darley, Mrs. Harry Bomberger, 14 ?, Mrs. John F. Nelson, 16 ?, Mrs. W. T. Dettor; Third Row L to R: 1 ?, "Foots" Dettor, Mrs. Douglas Vance 4 ?, Dr. Douglas Vance, Mrs. Deming Shear, Deming Shear, Wm. E. Hankins, Geo. S. Coyle, "Puss" Thomas, Bruce Lightner, Nate Adams, Sam'l. L. Brown, 14 ?, Josiah Eagle, "1 Key" Ney, 17 ?, 18 ?, "Billy" Wright, Maynard Darley; Fourth Row L to R: 1 ?, "Pinhead" Chamberlain, Alfred Martin, Walter S. Chisholm, Mason S. Byrd, Bernard W. Rannells, Dr. Ed Seabright
- "Still Together After 58 Years" 1976 June 13, 1 newspaper clipping w photo, 1 photocopy of newspaper clipping, 2 pp. (Box-folder 002-013)
  Identified in photo: G. B. Updike, Hunter Dunn, John Martin, Bruce Lightner, Stuart Rothwell, John Curtis, Nate Adams, George Coyle, Mason Byrd, Sam Brown, W. G. Vansant, D. D. Vance, Harry Wilson, Carroll Beach, Buseye Nelson, Deming Shear
- "The 'Good Life' of Dr. Doug" by Steve Alexander [n.d.], Newsletter, 4 pp. (Box-folder 002-014)
  This article is about Dr. Douglas D. Vance.
- Photocopies of photographs of University of Virginia football field [n.d.], Photocopy photographs with TN, 2 pp. (Box-folder 002-015)
- Reunion card and menu 1940 May 18, 2 Cards w autographs, 8 pp. (Box-folder 002-016)
  Reunion card has many Base Hospital 41 members' signatures.
- "Emory and Henry College Alumni News" 1962 July, Newsletter, 20 pp. (Box-folder 002-017)
- Newspaper clippings, re: Bernard Chamberlain 1983 June-July, 3 Photocopy newspaper clippings, 3 pp. (Box-folder 002-018)
  These articles were written after Chamberlain's death and include his obituary.
- Newspaper clippings re: Base Hospital 41 memebers 1941-1979, Photocopy newspaper clippings, 20 pp. (Box-folder 002-019)
  These include articles or obituaries about Alfred Newman Martin, Stuart S. Rothwell, Glenn B. Updike, Thomas Fitz-Hugh, and C. C. Faires.
- Replies to invitation to Base Hospital 41 reunion 1963, 106 Postcards, 212 pp. (Box-folder 002-020)
- Notecards with names and addresses of former Base Hospital 41 members [n.d.], 169 Notecards, 169 pp. (Box-folder 002-021)
- Replies to invitation to Base Hospital 41 reunion 1965-1966, 142 Postcards, 282 pp. (Box-folder 002-022)
- Invitation to Nineteenth Annual Meeting of the John Peyton Memorial Association 1970 March 24, 1 Mimeograph TMs, 2 pp. (Box-folder 002-023)
  Bernard P. Chamberlain was the secretary for the association.
- Invitation to Twenty-first Annual Meeting of the Peyton Society of Virginia 1972 April 1, 1 Mimeograph TMs, 4 pp. (Box-folder 002-024)
  Bernard P. Chamberlain was the secretary-general for the society.
- Invitation to Twenty-second Annual Meeting of the Peyton Society of Virginia 1973 March 8, 1 Mimeograph TMs, 4 pp. (Box-folder 002-025)
- Report on the Nineteenth Annual Meeting of the John Peyton Memorial Association 1970 June 15, 1 Mimeograph TMs, 12 pp. (Box-folder 002-026)
- Report of the Twenty-first Annual Meeting of the Peyton Society of Virginia 1972 June 10, 1 Mimeograph TMs w ANS, 14 pp. (Box-folder 002-027)
- Peytons of Virginia 1972, 1 Mimeograph TMs, 2 pp. (Box-folder 002-028)
  This genealogical chart includes dates from 1624-1880.
- The Peyton Society of Virginia application for membership 1972, 1 Mimeograph TMs, 1 TN (Box-folder 002-029)
- Program of Base Hospital 41 show 1918 December 7, 1 Mimeograph TMs, 1 p. (Box-folder 002-030)
  The show was given by the nurses, patients and the enlisted personnel.
- Scrapbook pages 1918-1919, Scrapbook excerpts, 6 pp. (Box-folder 002-031)
  The items include photographs, passes for George Coyle, tickets, and stamps.
- Reunion photograph of UVa pavilion [n.d.], 1 Photograph, B and W, 3.5x5 (Box-folder 002-032)
- Reunion photograph of UVa pavilion [n.d.], 1 Photograph, B and W, 3.5x5 (Box-folder 002-033)
- Reunion group photo taken on UVa grounds, people unidentified [n.d.], 1 Photograph, B and W, 3.5x5 (Box-folder 002-034)
- Reunion group photo taken on UVa grounds, people unidentified [n.d.], 1 Photograph, B and W, 3.5x5 (Box-folder 002-035)
- Reunion group photo taken on UVa grounds, people unidentified [n.d.], 1 Photograph, B and W 3.5x5 (Box-folder 002-036)
- Reunion photo taken on UVa grounds [n.d.], 1 Photograph, B and W 3.5x5 (Box-folder 002-037)
- Reunion photo taken on UVa grounds, people unidentified [n.d.], 1 Photograph, B and W 3.5x5 (Box-folder 002-038)
- Reunion group photo taken on UVa grounds, people unidentified [n.d.], 1 Photograph, B and W 3.5x5 (Box-folder 002-039)
- Reunion photo taken on UVa grounds, people unidentified [n.d.], 1 Photograph, B and W 3.5x5 (Box-folder 002-040)
- Reunion photo taken on UVa grounds, people unidentified [n.d.], 1 Photograph, B and W 3.5x5 (Box-folder 002-041)
- Reunion photo taken on UVa grounds, people unidentified [n.d.], 1 Photograph, B and W 3.5x5 (Box-folder 002-042)
- Reunion photo taken on UVa grounds, people unidentified [n.d.], 1 Photograph, B and W 3.5x5 (Box-folder 002-043)
- Reunion photo taken on UVa grounds, people unidentified [n.d.], 1 Photograph, B and W 3.5x5 (Box-folder 002-044)
- Reunion photo taken on UVa grounds, people unidentified [n.d.], 1 Photograph, B and W 3.5x5 (Box-folder 002-045)
- Reunion photo taken on UVa grounds [n.d.], 1 Photograph, B and W 3.5x5 (Box-folder 002-046)
- Photograph of Base Hospital 41 building with ambulances ca. 1918, 1 Photograph, B and W 4.75x6.5 (Box-folder 002-047)
- Photograph of Base Hospital 41 building with ambulances ca. 1918, 1 Photograph, B and W 4.75x6.5 (Box-folder 002-048)
- Photograph of Base Hospital 41 fracture ward ca. 1918, 1 Photograph, 2 copies, 1 B and W 4.5x6.25, 1 B and W 8x10 (Box-folder 002-049)
- Photograph of Camp Sevier, North Carolina 1918, 1 Photograph, B and W 4.75x6.5 (Box-folder 002-050)
- Photograph of the wards of Base Hospital 41 ca. 1918, 1 Photograph, B and W 4.75x6.5 (Box-folder 002-051)
- Photograph of outside of Base Hospital 41 ca. 1918, 1 Photograph, B and W 4.75x6.5 (Box-folder 002-052)
- Photograph of reunion attendees [n.d.], 1 Photograph, B and W 5x8 (Box-folder 002-053)
  L to R: Harry Wilson, Bernard Chamberlain, Walter Chisholm, Stuart Rothwell, Pete Perry, Sidney Powers, Mason Byrd, John Martin
- Photograph of reunion attendees [n.d.], 1 Photograph, 2 copies, B and W 8x10 (Box-folder 002-054)
- Photograph of reunion attendees [n.d.], 1 Photograph, 2 copies, B and W 8x10 (Box-folder 002-055)
- Photograph of reunion group, people unidentified 1965, 1 Photograph, 3 copies, B and W 8x10 (Box-folder 002-056)
  The photograph was taken at the Thomas Jefferson Inn.
- Letters regarding federal support for a history of Base Hospital 41 1966 September-October, 1 TLS, 2 Photocopied TLS (Box-folder 002-057)
  Letter from John B. Blake to Wilhelm Moll, Letter from David F. Kefauver to Wilhelm Moll, Letter from Wilhelm Moll to Bernard P. Chamberlain
- "Plan Base Hospital Veterans' Reunion" in Alumni News [n.d.], 1 Newsletter excerpt, 2 pp. (Box-folder 002-058)
- Glenn Brady Updike: autobiogaphy 1980 November 11, 1 Mimeograph TMs, 2 pp. (Box-folder 002-059)
  Updike's brief autobiography includes his time with Base Hospital 41.
- bookmark [n.d.], Bookmark, 1 p. (Box-folder 002-060)
  The bookmark has Randolph H. Perry's name typed on it.
- Photograph of a monument to Camp Sevier [n.d.], 1 Photograph, color 3.5x4.5 (Box-folder 002-061)
  The inscription reads: CAMP SEVIER IN MEMORY OF THE MEN WHO TRAINED HERE AND THOSE THAT MADE THE SUPREME SACRIFICE IN THE GREAT WORLD WAR. ERECTED BY AMERICAN LEGION AUXILIARY POST [unlclear] APRIL 6TH 1934.
- Photograph of unidentified building [n.d.], 1 Photograph, color 3.5x3.5 (Box-folder 002-062)
- "The New York Herald, European Edition-Paris" 1918 September 12, Newspaper, 4pp. (Box-folder 002-063)
- U.S. Army Base Hospital No. 41, Paris, France [Interior view of the fracture ward]. 1918, 8 X 10 B & W photograph (Box-folder 002-064)
  This photo was used in the Summer 1983 "Helix." It is Old Negative no. 10,292 B from the National Library of Medicine. St. Denis, Paris, France.
- Margaret Cowling Papers 1905-1983
  - "Between Convoys" 1918 December, 1 Newsletter, 2 copies, 1 photocopy, 8pp. (Box-folder 003-001)
  - Letter from Julian M. Cabell to Stephen Watts 1919 January 10, 1 Carbon copy TLS, 1 p. (Box-folder 003-002)
    The letter concerns the excellent work of Margaret Cowling.
  - "A Red Cross Nurse by Margaret Cowling [n.d.], 1 TMsS, 6 pp. (Box-folder 003-003)
    Cowling gives an account of her experiences with Base Hospital 41.
  - Margaret Cowling's Diploma from the University of Maryland Training School for Nurses 1905 May 10, 1 Diploma (Box-folder 003-004)
  - Exhibit information on Margaret Cowling [n.d.], 2 TMs, 1 AN, 6pp. (Box-folder 003-005)
    The exhibit was for the Claude Moore Health Sciences Library and includes "Margaret B. Cowling and her War Services as an American National Red Cross Nurse in Austria in 1915" by Dieter H. M. Groschel.
  - Margaret Cowling's record of service during World War I 1941 February 7, 1 TLS, 1 p. (Box-folder 003-006)
    The Office of the Surgeon General in the War Department certifies that Cowling took her oath of office on April 4, 1918 and was honorably discharged from the Army Nurse Corps on August 31, 1919.
  - Diploma to Certify the Silver Honorary Medal of the Red Cross received by Margaret Cowling 1915 September 15, 1 Diploma, 1 TD, 2 pp. (Box-folder 003-007)
    The diploma was given by Franz Salvator, Imperial Prince and Archduke of Austria, to recognize Cowling's military medical care given during World War I. An English translation of the German diploma is included.
  - Certificate of Red Cross Foreign Service for Margaret Cowling [n.d.], 1 Certificate (Box-folder 003-008)
    The Certificate expresses appreciation for Cowling's service to the Red Cross.
  - Certicate of Appreciation from the city of Baltimore, Maryland to Margaret Cowling 1919 November 27, 1 Certificate (Box-folder 003-009)
    The certificate expresses appreciation for Cowling's patriotic service with the American Forces.
  - "Margaret B. Cowling and her War Services as an American National Red Cross Nurse in Austria in 1915" by Dieter H. M. Groschel 1983 November 15, 1 TD, 3 pp. (Box-folder 003-010)
  - Photocopies of scenes of Camp Lee 1917, Photocopies of 3 photographs, 2 pp. (Box-folder 003-011)
    One photograph has two people identified: Ruth Moran and Ella Fife. Another photograph is of a hospital ward.
  - Photocopies of photographs of France and a medal ca. 1918, Photocopies of 2 Photographs and 1 Medal, 2 pp. (Box-folder 003-012)
    The photocopied photographs show St. Denis, Base Hospital 41, and a U. S. Army medal given to Ruth Moran.
  - "Patriae ac Humanitati, 1864-1914. K. D." [n.d.], 1 Cloth ribbon and 1 Metal medal (Box-folder 003-013)
  - Photocopy of a photograph of Reunion group, people unidentified 1965, 1 Photocopy of a photograph, 1 p. (Box-folder 003-014)
  - Letters regarding reunion 1965?-1966, 2 Photocopies 1 ALS, 1 TLS, 4 pp. (Box-folder 003-015)
    Letter from Agnus Brush to Ruth, Letter from Frances [Ricker] Appleton to Ruth
  - Minutes of Wichita General Hospital Board 1931 June 10, Carbon copy TD, 1 p. (Box-folder 003-016)
    The Board expresses appreciation for Margaret Cowling.
  - Letter from J. B. Casey to Margaret B. Cowling 1931 May 8, 1 TLS, 1 p. (Box-folder 003-017)
    Casey expresses the appreciation of the hospital staff for Cowling's work at the hospital.
  - Margaret Brand Cowling's license to be registered nurse in Texas 1928 July 14, 1 license, 2 pp. (Box-folder 003-018)
  - Margaret Brand Cowling's license to be registered nurse in Florida 1925 June 10, 1 license, 2 pp. (Box-folder 003-019)
  - Margaret Brand Cowling's license to be a nurse in Virginia 1916 June 26, 1 license, 1 p. (Box-folder 003-020)
  - Margaret Brand Cowling's license to be registered nurse in North Carolina 1905 December 11, 1 license, 1 p. (Box-folder 003-021)
  - Letter from Richard Oliver Phillips to Margaret Cowling 1915 April 3, 1 ALS, 3 pp. (Box-folder 003-022)
    Phillips writes on behalf of the Yonkers Homoeopathic Hospital and Maternity on the eve of Cowling's departure to work overseas in World War I.
  - Letter from Sarah K. Brent to Bernard P. Chamberlain 1970 September 8, 1 Carbon copy TL (Box-folder 003-023)
    Brent writes about the donation of papers belonging to Margaret Cowling.
  - Certificate of identity for Margaret Brand Cowling 19718 June 27, 1 Certificate with 1 Photo, 1 p. (Box-folder 003-024)
    The certificate was issued by the Unites States War Department.
  - Special passport for Margaret Brand Cowling 1915 April 24, 1 Certicate (Box-folder 003-025)
    The certificate was issued by the Unites States Department of State.
- Medal bearing inscription, "Journee du Poilu 1915/25-26 Decembre 1915, 1 boxed metal medal, with 1 AN (Box-folder 004-001)
  The note states that the medal was given to Capt. Walter Miller (Dutch) by the daughter of a French officer killed in W. W. I.
- Captions for Base Hospital 41 exhibit [n.d.], 1 TDS, 1 p. (Box-folder 004-002)
  The introduction and captions for the artifacts and photos included in the exhibit are given.
- Military orders 1919 April 13, 1 Photocopied TD, 1 p. (Box-folder 004-003)
  The order regards where nurses will be allowed on board a ship at sea.
- Letter from Sidney E. Powers to Comrades and Friends of B. H. 41 1965 June 9, 1 photocopied TLS w AN, 1 p. (Box-folder 004-004)
  Powers writes about the reunion.
- Letter from W. L. "Monk" Younger to Glenn B. Updike 1970 April 22, 1 Photocopies ALS (Box-folder 004-005)
  Younger thanks Updike for remembrances of Base Hospital 41.
- Letter from Nate to GLenn B. Updike 1970 May 1, 1 photocopies TLS (Box-folder 004-006)
  Nate gives Updike the names of some people who would enjoy reading Updike's diary from World War I.
- Excerpts from Glenn B. Updike's diary 1970 April 16, 1 TMs, 9 pp. (Box-folder 004-007)
  Updike's excerpts start on June 18, 1918 when he left Camp Sevier and end on May 1, 1919 when he was discharged from the U. S. Army.
- Letter from Glenn B. Updike to Mr. and Mrs. Bernard P. Chamberlain 1976 June 16, 1 TLS, 1 p. (Box-folder 004-008)
  Updike expresses appreciation for the reunion and considers diseminating additional excerpts from his World War I diary.
- Supplement from Glenn B. Updike's diary 1976 July 4, 1 TMs, 1 envelope, 7 pp. (Box-folder 004-009)
  Updike supplements the records taken from his diary on April 16, 1970 and includes information previously omitted.
- Letter Glenn B. Updike to Mr. and Mrs. Bernard Chamberlain 1978 October 10, 1 TLS, 1 p. (Box-folder 004-010)
  Updike's letter refers to enclosed photos which are now filed in Box 4, Folders 11-23.
- Photo taken at Elks National Home in Bedford 1978, 1 Photograph, color 3.25x3.5 (Box-folder 004-011)
  Photo shows men sitting in front of statue of an elk.
- Photo taken at Elks National Home in Bedford 1978, 1 Photograph, color 3.25x3.5 (Box-folder 004-012)
  Photo shows dining hall.
- Photo taken at Elks National Home in Bedford 1978, 1 Photograph, color 3.25x3.5 (Box-folder 004-013)
  Photo shows outside of building.
- Photo taken at Elks National Home in Bedford 1978, 1 Photograph, color 3.25x3.5 (Box-folder 004-014)
  L to R: Glenn B. Updike, Nate Adams
- Photo taken at Elks National Home in Bedford 1978, 1 Photograph, color 3.25x3.5 (Box-folder 004-015)
  L to R: Nate Adams, Glenn B. Updike
- Photo taken at Elks National Home in Bedford 1978, 1 Photograph, color 3.25x3.5 (Box-folder 004-016)
- Photo taken at Elks National Home in Bedford 1978, 1 Photograph, color 3.25x3.5 (Box-folder 004-017)
- Photo taken at Elks National Home in Bedford 1978, 1 Photograph, color 3.25x3.5 (Box-folder 004-018)
- Photo taken at Elks National Home in Bedford 1978, 1 Photograph, color 3.25x3.5 (Box-folder 004-019)
- Photo taken at Elks National Home in Bedford 1978, 1 Photograph, color 3.25x3.5 (Box-folder 004-020)
  Right: Nate Adams